Asian Sculpture Photograph Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Asian Sculpture Photograph Collection
1900-2005
VRC 4
Yale University Arts Library
7.9
19 boxes
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of Asian sculpture. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Conditions Governing Access
These materials are stored offsite at the Library Shelving Facility. For access to the materials, please make a request at the Art & Architecture Library.
Arrangement
Arranged by country or region. The country or region is further divided by medium, chronological period, and individual artists.
Scope and Contents
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of Asian sculpture. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Sculpture -- Asia; Photographs; Reproductions
- China., 828 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings.
  - Miscellaneous works., 11 (Box 1)
  - Chou Dynasty., 27 (Box 1)
  - Ch'in Dynasty., 15 (Box 1)
  - Han Dynasty., 113 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous works., 2 (Box 1)
    - Ceramics., 60 (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous works., 31 (Box 1)
      - Tiles., 29 (Box 2)
    - Metal., 23 (Box 2)
    - Stone., 28 (Box 2)
      - Miscellaneous works., 2 (Box 2)
      - Reliefs., 26 (Box 2)
  - Six Dynasties., 174 (Box 2–3)
    - Miscellaneous works., 3 (Box 3)
    - Ceramics., 27 (Box 3)
    - Metal., 28 (Box 3)
    - Stone., 116 (Box 3–4)
      - Miscellaneous works., 93 (Box 4)
      - Caves., 18 (Box 4)
      - Pagoda base., 7 (Box 5)
        - Hsiang-Tang-Shan, Workshop of, c.570., 7 (Box 5)
  - Sui Dynasty., 41 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous works., 20 (Box 5)
    - Stone., 21 (Box 5)
      - Miscellaneous works., 9 (Box 5)
      - Kuan-yin statues., 12 (Box 5)
  - T'ang Dynasty., 244 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous works., 7 (Box 5)
    - Ceramic., 96 (Box 5)
      - Miscellaneous subjects., 1 (Box 5)
      - Animals., 30 (Box 5)
      - Animals with figures., 23 (Box 6)
      - Figures., 32 (Box 6)
      - Reliefs., 10 (Box 6)
    - Metal., 27 (Box 6)
      - Animals., 10 (Box 6)
      - Figures., 17 (Box 6)
    - Stone., 101 (Box 7)
      - Miscellaneous works., 71 (Box 7)
      - Reliefs., 30 (Box 7)
    - Wood., 13 (Box 8)
  - Five Dynasties., 2 (Box 8)
  - Liao Dynasty., 19 (Box 8)
  - Sung Dynasty., 71 (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous works., 11 (Box 8)
    - Metal., 12 (Box 8)
    - Wood., 48 (Box 8)
  - Yuan Dynasty., 17 (Box 9)
  - Ming Dynasty., 57 (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous works., 15 (Box 9)
    - Metal., 13 (Box 9)
    - Stone., 16 (Box 9)
    - Wood., 13 (Box 9)
  - Ch'ing Dynasty., 37 (Box 10)
    - Unknown artists., 32 (Box 10)
    - Known artists., 5 (Box 10)
      - Miscellaneous artists, A-Z., 5 (Box 10)
        - Ch'ao-Tsung, active mid-XVII C., 1 (Box 10)
        - Ch'ien Lung, 1736-1795., 1 (Box 10)
        - K'ang Hsi, 1662-1723., 1 (Box 10)
        - Wu Chih-Fan., 2 (Box 10)
- Central Asia., 3 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous Works., 3 (Box 10)
- India., 150 (Box 10–11)
  Includes two folders of miscellaneous clippings, and two editions of the German magazineDu--Atlantis.
  - Miscellaneous works., 59 (Box 11)
  - Indus Valley Period., 2 (Box 11)
  - Maurya Dynasty., 1 (Box 11)
  - Sunga Dynasty., 5 (Box 11)
  - Early Andhra Dynasty., 2 (Box 11)
  - Kushan Dynasty., 54 (Box 12)
    - Mathura., 16 (Box 12)
    - Ghandhara., 38 (Box 12)
  - Later Andhra Dynasty., 7 (Box 12)
  - Gupta Dynasty., 3 (Box 12)
  - Pala-Sena Dynasty of Bengal., 2 (Box 12)
  - Rastrakuta Dynasty of the Deccan., 1 (Box 12)
  - Pallava Dynasty., 6 (Box 12)
  - Chola Dynasty., 6 (Box 12)
  - Vijayanagar Dynasty., 1 (Box 12)
  - Rajput Dynasty., 1 (Box 12)
- Japan., 586 (Box 12–13)
  - Jomon Period., 24 (Box 13)
  - Kofun Period., 33 (Box 13)
  - Suiko Period, 552-650., 57 (Box 14)
    - Unknown artists., 51 (Box 14)
      - Miscellaneous works., 14 (Box 14)
      - Nara., 13 (Box 14)
      - Tokyo., 24 (Box 14)
        - Miscellaneous locations., 1 (Box 14)
        - Imperial Household Collection., 23 (Box 14)
  - Late Yamato, 552-710., 66 (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous works., 20 (Box 14)
    - Nara., 46 (Box 14)
      - Miscellaneous locations., 5 (Box 14)
      - Horyu-ji Temple., 19 (Box 15)
        - Miscellaneous works., 11 (Box 15)
        - Tachibana Shrine., 8 (Box 15)
      - Yakushi-ji Temple., 22 (Box 15)
        - Miscellaneous works., 2 (Box 15)
        - Sho-Kannon, late VII C., 5 (Box 15)
        - Yakushi Triad, 688., 15 (Box 15)
  - Nara Period, 710-794., 272 (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous locations., 15 (Box 15)
    - Nara., 254 (Box 15)
      - Miscellaneous locations., 3 (Box 15)
      - Akishino-dera., 9 (Box 15)
      - Daian-ji Temple., 8 (Box 15)
      - Hokke-ji Temple., 3 (Box 16)
      - Horyu-ji Temple., 36 (Box 16)
      - Kaniman-ji Temple., 5 (Box 16)
      - Kofuki-ji Temple., 32 (Box 16)
      - Shinyakushi-ji Temple., 11 (Box 16)
      - Taema-dera., 6 (Box 16)
      - Oka-dera., 10 (Box 16)
      - Todai-ji Temple., 89 (Box 17)
      - Toshodai-ji Temple., 37 (Box 18)
      - Yakushi-ji Temple., 5 (Box 18)
    - Tokyo., 3 (Box 18)
  - Heian Period., 59 (Box 18)
    - Miscellaneous locations., 41 (Box 18)
    - Kyoto., 18 (Box 19)
  - Kamakura Period., 78 (Box 19)
    - Unknown artists., 28 (Box 19)
    - Known artists., 50 (Box 19)
      - Miscellaneous artists, A-Z., 23 (Box 19)
        - Gyokai, XIII C., 1 (Box 19)
        - Inchi, active 1252., 1 (Box 19)
        - Jokei, XIII C., 3 (Box 19)
        - Keishun, active 1240., 1 (Box 19)
        - Koen, active 1272., 2 (Box 19)
        - Kokei, active 1189., 2 (Box 19)
        - Kosho., 1 (Box 19)
        - Koshun, active 1311-1369., 2 (Box 19)
        - Koyu, active 1251., 1 (Box 19)
        - Kyoen, active 1226., 1 (Box 19)
        - Ono Goroemon., 1 (Box 19)
        - Tankei., 4 (Box 19)
        - Zen'en, active 1247., 1 (Box 19)
        - Zenkei, active 1249., 1 (Box 19)
      - Individual artists, A-Z., 27 (Box 19)
        - Kaikei., 10 (Box 19)
        - Koben., 5 (Box 19)
        - Unkei., 12 (Box 19)
  - XIX to XX Century., 3 (Box 19)